(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 1,
"subtitles": 2
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
4/2 JST 21時 Birthday Live 2025 Shiranui Flare
新衣装お披露目
April 2nd, 21:00 JST Shiranui Flare Birthday Live 2025
New Outfit Reveal
雑多に塗りたくられた
Painted in a jumble,
絵の具でぬかるんだ
muddy with paint,
世界を歩く
I walk through the world.
どこへでもゆけたけど
I could go anywhere,
どこだって同じさ
but it's the same everywhere.
濁ったキャンパスで
On a muddy canvas,
君だけが映えていた
only you were standing out.
自分のためだけに描いた
I painted only for myself;
僕は僕以外を
and I couldn't love anyone
愛せなかった
except for myself.
息を吸い込み 吐き出す
Inhaling and exhaling,
それだけの毎日に
in those days that were just that,
君が、君だけが映えていた
you, only you were standing out.
優しい嘘より傷つく真実が良いよ
A painful truth is better than a gentle lie.
孤独な自由より
Rather than a lonely freedom,
君といる不自由が良いよ
I'd rather be restricted with you.
夢中になった 夢中になった
I was absorbed, I was absorbed;
瞬間 五里霧中になった
the moment I was lost in the fog.
宇宙・未来・週末が晴れるかより 君を分けたい
Rather than the universe, future, or weekend being clear, I want to share moments with you.
夢中になった 夢中になった
I was absorbed, I was absorbed;
瞬間 筆は宙に舞った
the moment the brush danced in the air.
僕ら一つになれないよ
We can't become one,
混ざらないし濁らないまま ふたり
without mixing or becoming muddy, just the two of us.
マーブルが冴える
The marble stands out.
小さな諍いと許しと
With small quarrels and forgiveness,
罰とを分け合って
sharing punishments,
世界は回る
the world goes 'round.
みんな器用に笑うよな
Everyone smiles so skillfully, don't they?
そういうところ嫌い
I hate that about people.
君が、君だけが本当だ
You, only you are real.
優しく奪うより 傷つけても与えたいよ
I'd rather hurt you and give than gently take away.
孤独で満ちるより
Rather than being filled with loneliness,
君といて満たされずに居たいよ
I want to be with you and remain unfulfilled.
夢中になって 夢中になって
Being absorbed, being absorbed,
空間 色彩爆ぜた
the space and colors exploded.
見失ってもすぐわかるのさ
Even if I lose sight of you, I'll know immediately.
君は美しい
You are beautiful.
夢中になって 夢中になって
Being absorbed, being absorbed,
呼んだ言葉 宙に舞った
the words I called out danced in the air.
僕ら一つになれないし
We can't become one anyway,
だから君に触れたかった
that's why I wanted to touch you.
ごらん こんなに饒舌になったのに
Look, even though I've become this talkative,
言いそびれたことなら山ほどあるさ
there are mountains of things I failed to say.
路地裏で猫を見たとか
Like seeing a cat in a back alley,
雨上がりの夕映えが綺麗だとか
or how beautiful the evening glow is after the rain.
君といる不自由が
The restriction of being with you
心地いいとか
is comfortable, or something like that.
夢中になった 夢中になった
I was absorbed, I was absorbed;
瞬間 五里霧中になった
the moment I was lost in the fog.
御大層な未来予想図より
Rather than some grand map of the future,
君を信じたい
I want to believe in you.
I want to believe in you
夢中になった 夢中になった 瞬間
The moment, the moment I was entranced
筆は中に舞った
The brush danced in the air
僕ら一つになれないよ
We can't become one
混ざらないし濁らないよ
We don't mix or become muddy
嗚呼
Ah
ただ二人 マーブルが冴える
Just the two of us, the marble is clear
冴える 冴える
Clear, clear
雑多に塗りたくられた
Smeared with a variety of paints
絵の具でぬかるんだ
It's muddy with paint
世界を歩く
I walk the world
どこへでもゆけるけど
I can go anywhere, but
どこだって同じさ
it's the same everywhere
濁ったキャンパスで
On a muddy canvas
僕らだけが映えている
only we are shining
はーい！
Hi!
ということで、皆さん、こんふぃー！
So, hello everyone, Kon-fure!
ホロライブ3期生の不知火フレアでーす！
I'm Shiranui Flare from Hololive Gen 3!
今日は私の生誕祭ライブへ
Thank you all so much
きてくださ、く、く、くださってありがとうございます！
for coming to my birthday live today!
1曲目は私のオリジナルソング「マーブル」でした！
The first song was my original song "Marble"!
どうだった？
How was it?
なんか去年の8月に公開したオリ曲なんですけど、
It's an original song I released last August,
3Dで歌うのは今回初めてでして、
but this is the first time I've performed it in 3D.
まあ今回はですね、まあカバー曲だけじゃなくてオリ曲も、
Well, for this time, the setlist includes not only cover songs
まあちょっと入ってたりとかするかなーみたいな感じのセトリになっております。
but also some original songs... maybe? That's the vibe.
あ、そうだ！ あとですね、
Oh, that's right! Also,
まあちょっとみんな今見てて、もう気づいちゃった人いるかわかんないんですけど、
I'm not sure if anyone watching has already noticed,
なんとですね、ちょっとお化粧が変わりました！
but my makeup has actually changed a bit!
どうですか？ 可愛いでしょう？
What do you think? It's cute, right?
いろんな表情を今日は見せたいので、あのいっぱい楽しんで、
I want to show you many different expressions today, so I'd be happy
お写真もね、パシャパシャパシャパシャ撮ってくれると嬉しいなーなんて思うんですけど。
if you enjoy it and take lots of photos too.
あの、今回のね、あのステージ見てくださいこれ。めっちゃ綺麗でしょう？
Anyway, look at this stage. It's really beautiful, isn't it?
今回のステージあわせて作っていただきました。めちゃめちゃ可愛いでしょう？
They made this stage specifically for this event. It's incredibly cute, right?
ね、すごく可愛いステージになってます。
It's a really lovely stage.
まあね、今回はね、今年、屋外のステージになりました！
Well, this year, it's an outdoor stage!
初めてですね、屋外。
This is my first time doing an outdoor live.
お城とか、なんかテーマパークみたいな感じで可愛く作っていただきました。
It was made to look cute, like a castle or a theme park.
そしてですね、なんと今年の生誕では、
And also, surprisingly, in this birthday live,
ライブ後半には新衣装のお披露目があります！
there will be a new outfit reveal in the latter half!
お待たせしました！
Thank you for waiting!
100万人のご褒美みたいな感じになってます。
It's like a 1-million-subscribers reward.
このステージに合った感じの衣装をね、あの考えて作っていただきました。
I had an outfit made that fits this stage.
可愛い衣装になりますので、
It's going to be a cute one,
どんな衣装なのか予想しながらお披露目まで、いやお披露目後も楽しんでもらえたら嬉しいです！
so please enjoy guessing what it's like before and after the reveal!
今回のハッシュタグはこちら！
The hashtag for this time is here!
こちらですね！ #不知火フレア生誕祭2025 です。
It's this one: #ShiranuiFlareBirthday2025.
感想やスクショ、たくさんポストしてくれると嬉しいです！
I'd be happy if you post lots of thoughts and screenshots!
それではですね、次の曲へ早速いこうと思います。
Now, let's move on to the next song.
次の曲からはゲストもたくさん登場しますので、
Many guests will appear from the next song onwards,
誰が来るのか、わくわくわくわくしながら楽しみにしててください！
so look forward to seeing who's coming!
それでは、どうぞ！
Well then, please enjoy!
君の心が火必要で
Your heart is fire-essential
僕の心は火必要だ
And my heart is fire-essential
全部をひっくり返しちゃうような狂騒をくれよ
Give me a frenzy that turns everything upside down
いけない fool logic
Inconvenient Fool Logic
純粋でも 順調でも 順風でもなんだかんだ
Whether pure, steady, or smooth, somehow
すべてが つまびらか とかありえないぜ
it's impossible for everything to be obvious
いぶかったり 着飾ったり 言い合ったり ピーチクパーチク
Doubtful, dressing up, or arguing back and forth
解決の手立てはなかなか 難攻不落か
The means of resolution are quite impregnable
さあ ど真ん中へ Take zero に 腹を括って Yeah!
Now, to the center, steel yourself for take zero, yeah!
平行線のランデブー そんなんじゃなくたっていいじゃないか
A rendezvous of parallel lines, isn't it fine even if it's not like that?
傾向はどうなっていく? それも心配したって No response
How will the trend go? Even if you worry about that, there's no response
登せ 登れ 有望スタンスのストーリーに保証はないけれど
Get dizzy, climb up, there's no guarantee in the story of a promising stance
デートしてくれ ありったけ
Go on a date with me, with everything you've got
いけない fool logic
Inconvenient Fool Logic
いけないfool logic 危ないロープだって 全世界一番高い
Forbidden fool logic, even on a dangerous rope, the highest in the world
挑戦しない理由はない
There's no reason not to take the challenge
指先が闇だなんて言い出した奴から順番に
Starting with those who said their fingertips are in darkness
さよなら
Say goodbye
最後に笑うのは僕らだろう
We'll be the ones laughing in the end
君の心が必要で
Your heart is necessary
僕の心は必要だ
And my heart is necessary
あてずっぽ繰り返すように見えてるとしたって
Even if it looks like we're just repeating random guesses
結局僕らが勝利しちゃうから 競争はくれよ
In the end, we're going to win, so give us the competition
晴天なり 曇天なり 結構結構
Fine weather or cloudy, it's all good, all good
ノイズごと着ていく ぷっとか世話がないぜ
Wearing the noise itself, I can't be bothered with small stuff
流動的共感ハッピー うぜえよな
Fluid empathetic happy, so annoying, right?
余さず定めで食べるが獅子の嗜みさ
Eating fate without leaving a crumb is a lion's taste
最大花咲かせ
Let the biggest flowers bloom
場所はディナーの後で
The place is after dinner
正解はここにあるなんてない
The correct answer isn't here
映画の世界みたいに
Like in a world of movies
言葉にできそうなら
If it could be put into words
そっか それは魔法じゃない
Well then, it wouldn't be magic
Shake the world 遊んでいたいだけ ノリよりアライヴ・イン・シチュエーション
Shake the world, I just want to play, 'Alive in Situation' over just rhythm
王様はきっといなくなる
The King will surely disappear
ならば僕らはどうしよう
In that case, what shall we do?
展望を見るに応じて
Depending on the view of the outlook
今は立ち入り禁止 sorry give up
Entry is forbidden for now, sorry, give up
平行線 並んでムズい 息絶えるまで
Parallel lines, it's hard to stay in line until our last breath
傾向はどうだっていい もうどうでもいいです ぶん投げ
Trends don't matter, I don't care anymore, just throw it away
アイデアが上々
The ideas are excellent
満パンじゃなきゃ新世紀エンジンで対応しろ
If you're not full, handle it with a new century engine
じっとしててくれ ありがとうな
Stay still, thanks
いけないfool logic
Forbidden fool logic
手札にバッドジョーカーがあったって ためらわない
Even if there's a Bad Joker in my hand, I won't hesitate
単刀直入 Shake the world
Direct and straightforward, Shake the world
いけないfool logic 危ないロープだって
Forbidden fool logic, even on a dangerous rope
全世界一番高い 挑戦しない理由はない
The highest in the whole world, there's no reason not to challenge it
指先が闇だなんて言い出した奴から順番に
Starting with those who said their fingertips are in darkness
さよなら
Say goodbye
最後に笑うのは僕らだろう
We'll be the ones laughing in the end
君の心が必要で
Your heart is necessary
僕の心は必要だ
And my heart is necessary
あてずっぽ繰り返すように見えてるとしたって
Even if it looks like we're just repeating random guesses
結局僕らが勝利しちゃうから 競争はくれよ
In the end, we're going to win, so give us the competition
願った勇敢な選択の
The brave choice I wished for
未来を今
Of the future, now
照らしてく
I'll light it up
利己的な感情 ぶつけ合っちゃ
Colliding with our selfish emotions
まだ見えないね
We still can't see it
逃げてきた分の距離を埋める
To bridge the distance we ran from
ほら 旅に出よう
Come, let's go on a journey
最果てなんて 見られなくても
Even if we can't see the ends of the earth
命を燃やして 今を生きていくだけだから
Because we'll just keep burning our lives and living for now
願った存在の証明を
The proof of existence I wished for
この音振るわせ続けて
Keep letting this sound vibrate
振りかざしてきたから
Because I've been brandishing it
後悔はいらない 手を取り合って
No need for regrets, taking each other's hands
重ね合って
Overlapping together
受け止めて進んでいく
Accepting it and moving forward
示された答え選ぶより
Rather than choosing a given answer
新しい夢を目指すから
I'll aim for a new dream
眩しい道を歩いていこう
Let's walk down the radiant path
リスクを秘めた道にだって
Even on a path hidden with risks
きっと夢はある
There's surely a dream
二人しかない可能性を
The possibilities that only we two share
ほら 見つけよう
Look, let's find them
最果てよりも
More than the ends of the earth
今を見つめて
Looking at the present
どんな結末でも
No matter the outcome
まだ変えていけるはずだから
I should still be able to change it
誓った存在の証明を
The proof of existence I swore
一人で見てきた空も
The sky I gazed at alone
無駄じゃないと知ったから
Because I learned it wasn't in vain
簡単じゃなくていい
It doesn't have to be easy
手を取り合って未来だって
Take each other's hands, even the future
受け止めて進んでいく
I'll accept it and move forward
示された答え選ぶより
Rather than choosing a given answer
眩しい道を歩いて行こう
Let's walk down a radiant path
不甲斐なくて泣いた
I cried out of helplessness
冷たい風の夜
On a night of cold wind
もっと強くなりたいと願った
I wished to become stronger
存在の証明を
The proof of existence
鼓動震わせ続けて
Keep making my heart tremble
繰り返してきたから
Because I've been repeating it
後悔はいらない
No need for regrets
手を取り合って過去だって
Take each other's hands, even the past
受け止めて進んでいく
I'll accept it and move forward
示された答え選ぶより
Rather than choosing a given answer
新しい夢を目指すから
Because I'm aiming for a new dream
眩しい道を歩いて行こう
Let's walk down a radiant path
Season
作詞・作曲・編曲：渡辺翔 / 瀬川あづさ
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: Sho Watanabe / Azusa Segawa
ほらまた君の前で　涙を見せてしまった
Look, I've shown my tears in front of you again
何があってもずっと　離れないでいてくれた
No matter what happened, you stayed by my side
誰かを守り抜くと　誰かに罪を作る
To protect someone through to the end, creates a sin for someone else
生きるほど愛を知って　心は強くなる
The more I live, the more I know love, and my heart becomes stronger
目の奥に映る　過去の傷は
The wounds of the past reflected in the depths of my eyes
私しか飲み干せないから
Are something only I can swallow down
君の存在だけで世界は　万華鏡みたいに
Just with your presence, the world is like a kaleidoscope
くるくる回って光が射す
Spinning 'round and 'round, the light shines through
変わる季節と　変わらない笑い声
The changing seasons and unchanging laughter
君は思い出にならないよ
You won't become a mere memory
ここにいるから
Because you are here
真夜中ベンチで言った　まだかさぶたの過去を
The past that was still a scab, I talked about it on that midnight bench
綺麗に剥がしたの　あたたかい君の手
Your warm hand peeled it off so cleanly
沈黙続いたあと　降り出す雨に気付いて
After a silence, we noticed the rain starting to fall
そのまま言えずにいる　ごめんね、ありがとう
I'm still unable to say it... "I'm sorry," and "Thank you"
月日が経つほど　純粋な
As the days and months pass, those pure
言葉は飲み込むけど
Words, I swallow them down, but...
いつかまた独りになっても　星のない夜でも
Even if I become alone again someday, even on a starless night
あの頃の孤独とは違うだろう
It will surely be different from the loneliness back then
泣いてばかりな　青い日のわたしには
For me in those immature days, when I did nothing but cry
会いたいと思う顔さえも　浮かばなくて
Not even a single face I wanted to see would come to mind
桜舞う春　花火が夜空を
Spring with fluttering cherry blossoms, fireworks coloring the night sky
染めていく夏
In the summer
もみじ揺れる秋
Autumn with swaying maple leaves
雪降る冬
Winter with falling snow
すべてに君が
In everything, you...
居てほしい
...I want you to be there.
君の存在だけで世界は
Just by your existence, the world...
万華鏡みたいに
...is like a kaleidoscope.
くるくる回って
Spinning round and round,
光が射す
light shines through.
変わる季節と
With the changing seasons,
変わらない笑い声
and unchanging laughter.
走る君に合わせ景色は
Matching you as you run, the scenery...
色付くから
...is gaining color.
どうか忘れないで
Please don't forget,
今その目に映る幸せ
the happiness reflected in your eyes right now.
最高ですかー！
Is it the best?!
最高でーす！
It's the best!
幸せですかー！
Are you happy?!
幸せでーす！
I'm happy!
お付き合いしちゃって
Going out together,
同棲とか始めちゃって
and even starting to live together,
好き好き大好き困っちゃう
I love you, I love you so much, it's trouble,
新郎新婦になりたい
I want us to become groom and bride.
フレイナ！
Flare-Ina!
フレあとイナは？
And Flare and Ina?
てぇてぇ！
Precious!
婚約指輪はどうするの
What about the engagement ring?
給料半年分くらい
About half a year's salary?
新居の間取りはどうするの
What about the layout of our new home?
7LDKKK
世界一可愛くなるから
Since I'll become the cutest in the world,
世界一カッコ良くなってね
please become the coolest in the world.
愛してるも毎日言って
Say "I love you" every day too,
あー大好きも忘れずに
and don't forget "Ah, I love you so much".
お父さん、お母さん
Father, Mother,
お許しください
please give us your blessing.
結婚します
We're getting married.
小指をもっともっともっと繋いでるぜ
We're linking pinkies more and more and more!
おねがい
Please!
人生最高の日。に
On the best day of our lives,
祝福を受ける二人
the two of us receive blessings.
好き好き大好き困っちゃう
I love you, I love you so much, it's trouble,
新郎新婦の入場
The entrance of the groom and bride!
大好きな人
The person I love,
大切な人
the person who's important to me.
力を合わせて生きて行きます
We'll join forces and live our lives together.
フレイナ！
Flare-Ina!
フレあとイナは？
And Flare and Ina?
てぇてぇ！
Precious!
新婚旅行はどうしよう
What should we do for the honeymoon?
沖縄で水着とか着たい
I want to wear a swimsuit in Okinawa.
小樽では何を食べようか
What should we eat in Otaru?
私の手作り料理
My home-cooked meal.
世界一可愛いお前と
With you, the cutest in the world,
生涯添い遂げると誓う
I vow to stay with you for life.
愛してると毎日言うよ
I'll say "I love you" every day,
いやベタベタ毎日抱き合うわ
No, we'll hug each other every day!
おじいちゃん、おばあちゃん
Grandpa, Grandma,
娘もついに
your daughter finally...
結婚します
...is getting married.
仲良しの秘訣？
The secret to getting along?
そうね、夫婦として当たり前のことを当たり前にやるだけなんだけど
Well, we just do the usual things as a couple as a matter of course.
強いて言うならば
If I had to say,
二人の愛
it's the love between the two of us!
人生最高の日。に
On the best day of our lives,
祝福を受ける二人
the two of us receive blessings.
好き好き大好き困っちゃう
I love you, I love you so much, it's trouble,
新郎新婦の入場
The entrance of the groom and bride!
大好きな人
The person I love,
大切な人
the person who's important to me.
力を合わせて生きて行きます
We'll join forces and live our lives together.
もーそーおーち
Reality check!
人生最高の日。に
On the best day of our lives,
祝福を受ける二人
the two of us receive blessings.
好き好き大好き困っちゃう
I love you, I love you so much, it's trouble,
新郎新婦の入場
The entrance of the groom and bride!
大好きな人
The person I love,
大切な人
the person who's important to me.
力を合わせて生きて行きます
We'll join forces and live our lives together.
フレイナ最強！
Flare-Ina are the strongest!
最高ですかー！
Is it the best?!
最高でーす！
It's the best!
幸せですかー！
Are you happy?!
幸せでーす！
I'm happy!
最高ですかー！
Is it the best?!
最高でーす！
It's the best!
幸せですかー！
Are you happy?!
幸せでーす！
I'm happy!
だいしきゅーだいしゅき
I love you so much!
1, 2, get your 密口 one, two,
シュギシュギで弾けたB.B. my ルーレット
1, 2, get your honey, one, two,
B.B. my roulette popping with my logic
グッと刺さったドキドキ 痛い痛い痛い
Pounding heart pierced through, it hurts, hurts, hurts
A.Q. Thank you! 好きマキのQ
1ミリの隙間にダイビング
A.Q. Thank you! Love-roll Q,
diving into a one-millimeter gap
Loveスタンプ全部コンプして UP いざ いざ いざ いざ せーの！
Collecting all the love stamps, UP! Ready, set, go!
待って 今日はゴッド・メンタル
Wait, today I have a god-like mentality
いさましきチャレンジャー
A brave challenger
ちょっとだけセンチメンタル
Just a little bit sentimental
だいしきゅーだいしゅき 1, 2, 3, はい！
ASAP, I wuv you! 1, 2, 3, here we go!
まみむめもめもめも 見れないの
Ma-mi-mu-me-mo-mo-mo-mo, I can't look at you
たしつてとてとてと 手が触れて
Ta-shi-tsu-te-to-te-to-te-to, our hands touch
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ
Fall in love with me ASAP
もっとキュキュキュキュと強制ロック
A tighter and tighter forced lock
あのねクリオネ透けてるハート
You know, like a sea angel's transparent heart
でもねこの胸 見透かさないで
But don't see through my heart
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ
Fall in love with me ASAP
私じゃないなんて終わってんね
If it's not me, you're hopeless
1, 2, get your 密口 one, two,
シュギシュギでカラフル・キューティー・マインド
1, 2, get your honey, one, two,
A colorful, cutie mind with my logic
ルーレット ちょっとストップ いたい急死
いや いや いや でも せーの！
Roulette, stop for a second, a sudden death
No, no, no, but... Ready, set, go!
待って 今日はもっとめでて
Wait, cherish me more today
うらわしきチャレンジャー
A beautiful challenger
ハート描いたオートメーション
Automation that drew a heart
だいしきゅーだいしゅき 1, 2, 3, はい！
ASAP, I wuv you! 1, 2, 3, here we go!
まみむめもめもめも にしてほしいの
Ma-mi-mu-me-mo-mo-mo-mo, I want you to make me yours
なにぬねのねのねの 恋の子猫と
Na-ni-nu-ne-no-ne-no-ne-no, with a kitten in love
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ
Fall in love with me ASAP
もっとキュキュキュキュと強制ロック
A tighter and tighter forced lock
あのねマリオネ操られレディ
You know, a marionette controlled lady
でもねそれもね悪くはないね
But that's not too bad either
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ
Fall in love with me ASAP
私じゃないなんて終わってんね
If it's not me, you're hopeless
フレンドリーなふりして 周波数を乱さないで
Don't mess with my frequency while pretending to be friendly
いわくつきの魅惑のリスナー
A charming listener with a history
ビビビビ... ビビビビ...
Zap zap zap zap... Zap zap zap zap...
まみむめもめもめも 見れないの
Ma-mi-mu-me-mo-mo-mo-mo, I can't look at you
たしつてとてとてと 手が触れて
Ta-shi-tsu-te-to-te-to-te-to, our hands touch
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ
Fall in love with me ASAP
もっとキュキュキュキュと強制ロック
A tighter and tighter forced lock
あのねクリオネ透けてるハート
You know, like a sea angel's transparent heart
でもねこの胸 見透かさないで
But don't see through my heart
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ
Fall in love with me ASAP
私じゃないなんて...
If it's not me...
終わってんね！
You're hopeless!
まみむめもめもめも 見れないの
Ma-mi-mu-me-mo-mo-mo-mo, I can't look at you
たしつてとてとてと 手が触れて
Ta-shi-tsu-te-to-te-to-te-to, our hands touch
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ
Fall in love with me ASAP
もっとキュキュキュキュと強制ロック
A tighter and tighter forced lock
あのねクリオネ透けてるハート
You know, like a sea angel's transparent heart
でもねこの胸 見透かさないで
But don't see through my heart
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ
Fall in love with me ASAP
私じゃないなんて終わってんね
If it's not me, you're hopeless
どこまでも続くこの空のように
Just like this sky that continues forever
ずっと ずっと ずっと 青さを持って
Forever, forever, forever, staying blue
遥か遠くまで 青く在れ
Go to the far distance and stay blue
過ぎ去った日々と 記憶の回路に沿って
Following the past days and the circuit of memories
心の声が 頬を伝った そっと
The voice of my heart softly trickled down my cheek
失ったピースを 数えてまた どうしてか
Counting the lost pieces again, for some reason
手を伸ばすんだ 胸の奥
I reach out from the depths of my heart
わかってるよ
I know
進む意味を
The meaning of moving forward
君はくれたんだ
You gave it to me
どこまでも続くこの空を 駆け抜けて
Running through this sky that continues forever
鮮やかな青になれたら
If I could become a vivid blue
どこまでも響く旅になる
It will be a journey that echoes everywhere
大袈裟でもいい
Even if it's an exaggeration
咲き誇れ ただ
Just bloom in full glory
伝えたいから
Because I want to tell you
言葉が今 音になって
My words are now becoming sounds
空振った日々の
In the days spent in vain,
孤独なアイロニー
the lonely irony.
ずっと声にならない
Forever unable to speak,
心の奥の「本当」
the "truth" deep within my heart.
気づかなかったフリをして
Pretending not to notice,
誤魔化した
I glossed it over.
ぼやける線と　滲む青
Blurring lines and bleeding blue.
何度だって　塗り直すよ
I'll repaint it again and again,
消せない程に
until it's indelible.
どこまででも続くこの空も
This sky that stretches on forever...
君となら怖くない　風追い越して
isn't scary if I'm with you, overtaking the wind.
どこまでも行けるさ　想うまま
We can go anywhere, just as we wish.
描く未来も　超えてゆけ
Go beyond even the future we draw.
さあ　派手なくらいに
Come on, as flashy as can be,
想いを今　音に乗せて
put your feelings onto the sound now.
瞼の裏、見える景色
The scenery I see behind my eyelids...
君の声で気づけた　あの日の青
is the blue of that day I realized through your voice.
Into the skies with you, forever they'll be blue
歌い続けるよ
I'll keep on singing.
どこまでだって　響くさきっと
It'll surely resonate anywhere.
不器用だっていい　恥じるな
It's okay to be clumsy, don't be ashamed.
笑われたっていい
It's okay to be laughed at,
止まるな　この気持ちは消えないから
don't stop, because these feelings won't fade away.
どこまででも続くこの空を
Through this sky that stretches on forever...
駆け抜けて　鮮やかな　青になれたら
if I can run through and become a vivid blue,
どこまででも響く　歌になる
it'll become a song that resonates everywhere.
大げさでもいい　咲き誇れ
It's okay if it's exaggerated, bloom proudly.
ただ　伝えたいから
Just because I want to tell you,
言葉を今、音に乗せて
put words onto the sound now.
青く染まるよ
It's dyeing blue.
そんな、なんだなんだ戦いだよ、意味分かんない。
Wait, what's this, it's a battle? I don't get it.
ピー、ピー
Pi, Pi
カニ、カニ、カニ、カニってことで。
Crab, crab, crab, crab, and with that...
アイリスに来てもらいました！
We have IRyS here!
わあ、やったー！来たぞー！遊園地に来たぞー！
Whoa, yay! I'm here! I'm at the amusement park!
いえー、フレアフェスティバルだー！
Yeah, it's Flare Festival!
めっちゃ楽しそうなんだけどここ。
This place looks like so much fun.
でしょ？
Right?
So hi-RyS, it's IRyS from hololive English, hololive EN and ID の IRyS です。
So hi-RyS, it's IRyS from hololive English, hololive EN and ID's IRyS desu.
今だいたい台本読んだね、多分ね。
You pretty much just read the script just now, probably.
そう、台本に書いてあるからとりあえず。
Yeah, it's written in the script so for now...
自己紹介ありがとう。
Thanks for the introduction.
ということでね、今日は来てくれてどうもありがとうございます。
So, thank you very much for coming today.
こちらこそ、呼んでいただきありがとうございます！
Likewise, thank you for inviting me!
やーね、あの。
Yeah, um...
どうですか、オリ曲なんですよ。私とアイリスの。
How was it? It's our original song. Mine and IRyS's.
初めての。「青く在れ」。
Our first. "Ao ku are".
めちゃくちゃエモい曲やろ。
It's a super emotional song, right?
ねえ、なんでこの曲出したかみたいなのは、まあ話してると思うんだけどさ。
Right? I think we've talked about why we released this song.
あの、出した時にね。
Um, when we released it.
ふーたんが声かけてくれたんだもんね。
Fuu-tan was the one who reached out to me.
ふーたんがオリ曲出そうよって。めちゃ嬉しい誘いしてくれて。
Fuu-tan said "let's release an original song". She gave me a really happy invitation.
2人でさ、あのいろいろね、やってるじゃん。エモいゲームを。
The two of us have been doing various things, right? Like emotional games.
エモい、エモい、エモい。イクラを乱獲したりとか、いろいろしてるわけですよ。
Emo, emo, emo. We've been over-harvesting salmon roe and doing all sorts of things.
なんですけど、やっぱりね2人とも歌が好きで、歌活動とかもね、してるわけで。
But, after all, we both love singing and are doing singing activities.
歌とかね。
Singing and such.
そうなの。で、私、あの、オリ曲とかを...
Exactly. And for me, um, for my original songs...
作る過程で聴いた曲の中で...
among the songs I listened to in the process of making them...
「あ、もうこれめちゃくちゃアイリスと歌いたい」と思った曲が、聴いたらもうあったりとかして。
there was a song where I thought, "Ah, I really want to sing this with IRyS."
素敵な曲だね。
It's a wonderful song.
そう、それはやるに決まってる。
Yeah, of course we're doing it.
アイリスに「一緒に歌わない？」って聞いたら...
When I asked IRyS "won't you sing with me?"...
「やだ」って言ったんだよね。
she said "No," right?
そしたら無くなったんです。
Then it was gone.
そう、今のはこの世界線はまた別の世界線だからね。受けた世界線だから。
Right, that just now was another world line. This is the world line where she accepted.
そう、だから現実とはね、違うんだよみんな。
Yeah, so it's different from reality, everyone.
そう、現実ではね断ったから。
Yeah, because in reality I refused.
これ終わった後はなかったことになるからこの曲。
After this is over, this song will be treated as if it never happened.
やめて。なかったことにならないで。
Stop it. Don't let it become non-existent.
まあね、私とアイリスでまた何か歌いたいけどね。
Well, I want to sing something with IRyS again, though.
またやりたいね、歌。
I want to do it again, singing.
歌はあんまりやってないからね配信。いつも言われてたのなかリスナーさんに。
We haven't done singing much on streams. Listeners were always telling us.
フレアリスが好きなリスナーさんには、「2人の曲出さないの？」っていつも言われてた。
Listeners who like Flare-IRyS always asked, "Aren't you going to release a song together?"
そうなの？
Is that so?
そうだよ。そう言ってもらえて嬉しいな。
Yeah. I'm happy they said that.
なので、また歌おうよ。
So, let's sing again.
歌おう。
Let's sing.
あと何か、サバイバルも...
And also, maybe some survival...
サバイバル... 森の中のサバイバルも...
Survival... A survival in the forest too...
そうだよ、森のサバイバルとか...
That's right, like a forest survival...
イクラも取ろう
Let's catch some salmon roe too.
一狩りも行こうよ
Let's go for a hunt too.
一狩りも行こうよ。一狩りもしたいね
Let's go for a hunt. I want to go hunting too.
ということでね、はい
And with that...
またね、あの、フレアイリスは今後もね、あの、いっぱい続いていきますんで
Well, "Flare-IRyS" will continue to do lots of things together in the future.
フレアイリス、これからもよろしくお願いします
Flare-IRyS, we look forward to your continued support!
イェーイ！
Yay!
あ、私が吐くんだね
Oh, I'm the one spitting it out?
吐けるんだ
I can spit?
吐けるな
Don't spit.
バイバイ！
Bye-bye!
はい、ということで不知火フレア生誕祭、まだまだ続きます
Alright, the Shiranui Flare Birthday Festival is still going on!
お持ちかねの新衣装は... そろそろかな？
The new outfit you've been waiting for... is it about time?
うん。ちょっとこれだとわかんないんですけど
Hmm, I can't really tell from this...
まあ、次の曲、いきましょう！
Well, let's head to the next song!
Unhappy? ねえ目を見開いた子よ
Unhappy? Hey, you with the wide-open eyes.
至らぬ不心得者も 精一杯目指せよ
Even you thoughtless ones, aim with all your might.
生きているんだし
Because you're alive.
目を逸らした過去も 退屈な未来も
The past you looked away from, and the boring future.
カウンセリングやれやれ
Counseling, oh boy.
古今東西 ピースピース
All times and places, peace, peace.
Unhappy
Unlucky
Be happy
Undead
ねえねねね 何だかどうして戦っているようなそんな気がするの
Hey, hey, hey, I somehow feel like I'm fighting.
触れられない 触れたくもない
I can't touch it, I don't want to touch it.
過去の自分 自分 自分 自分と
With the past me, me, me, me.
とっくに死んでる
Already dead.
透明な亡霊と対決
Confrontation with a transparent ghost.
痛い経験 痛い記憶の奥
A painful experience, deep in painful memories.
残念 もういないのに
Too bad, even though it's already gone.
あれ？そっちが良い？アイロニーね
Huh? Is that better? How ironic.
透かされているのは現在の自分？
Is the one being seen through the current me?
何せ 消えないレッテル
Anyway, the label that won't disappear.
Yes！要はコンプレックス
Yes! In short, a complex.
取り憑かれているみたい
Like being possessed.
泣きついたまま
While still crying.
まだ 離れられない
Still unable to leave.
有りし日の自分
The me from days gone by.
死んじゃいない
Not dead.
お前とお前の連鎖
The chain of you and you.
生きていることは変わり続けることだ
To live is to keep changing.
不幸に甘んじて満足するなよ
Don't be content with wallowing in unhappiness.
幸せになろうとしないなんて卑怯だ
It's cowardly not to try to be happy.
この世 この世は奇奇怪怪ファンタジー
This world, this world is a strange fantasy.
次は鬼が出るか 蛇が出るか
Will a demon or a snake come out next?
出会って 遭って やっと始まる物語
Met, encountered, the story finally begins.
さあ 人か化け物か
Now, is it a human or a monster?
閑話休題 ピースピース
To get to the point, peace, peace.
Past & Future
Can't change the Past
Run for the Future
何だかどうして未来になんぞ
Somehow, why to the future?
何の希望も期待出来ないような気がして
Feeling like I can't hope or expect anything.
もうずいぶん生きてる
I've lived quite a long time.
既視感とテンプレで食傷
Fed up with déjà vu and templates.
素敵な出来事の気配もない
No sign of anything wonderful happening.
残念
Too bad.
積んだ経験の因果
The causality of accumulated experience.
形骸化された神話と退屈な進化
Formalized myths and boring evolution.
要は刺激が欲しいんだ
In short, I want stimulation.
飽きちゃった 慣れちゃった
I'm bored, I'm used to it.
何て 整ったガイダンス
What well-organized guidance.
増えるコンプライアンス
Increasing compliance.
蓋されていくみたい
It's like being shut in.
吸い尽くして
Drink it all up.
あれも これも どれも
That, this, all of it.
同じ味がする
Tastes the same.
死んじゃいない
Not dead.
お前とお前の連鎖
The chain of you and you.
いつも過去も未来も現在にあるんだ
The past and future are always in the present.
生きていることを愚直に果たせよ
Fulfill the act of living honestly.
目指せハッピーエンド
Aim for a happy ending.
死んじゃいない
Not dead.
お前に言ってるんだ
I'm talking to you.
幸せを諦めてしまうな 人で在れ
Don't give up on happiness, remain human.
ただ苦しみに慣れて
Just getting used to the pain.
耐えているだけじゃ死んでいるも同然
Enduring is the same as being dead.
屍のアンデッド
A corpse undead.
Unhappy? ねえ目を見開いた子よ
Unhappy? Hey, you with the wide-open eyes.
至らぬ不心得者も 精一杯目指せよ
Even you thoughtless ones, aim with all your might.
生きているんだろ
You're alive, aren't you?
不幸に浸るも 幸せになるのも
Wallowing in misfortune or becoming happy.
そう全部全部お前だ
Yes, it's all, all you.
古今東西一切合切森羅万象ピースピース
All times, all things, all of creation, peace, peace.
Past & Future
Can't change the Past
Run for the Future
人なる所 いつも得難い事
Where people are, things are always hard to come by.
生き抜けこの化け物ばかりの物語
Survive this story full of monsters.
P-O-P-P-Y
POP-IN 2
Go!
P-O-P-P-Y
POP-IN 2
隠して
Hide it.
どこへ どこへ どこへも連れてって
Anywhere, anywhere, take me anywhere.
秘密で
In secret.
君を 君を 君を 探せるかな
I wonder if I can find you, you, you.
アロアロ 私は行く先々
Alo-alo, wherever I go.
後先先なら考えない
I won't think about the consequences.
パカラパカラ 目もビックリ玉手箱
Clop-clop, eyes surprised like a treasure box.
手っ取り早く虜になれよ
Hurry up and become a captive.
揺らして
Shake it.
悪巧みだけじゃ 足りないでしょう
Evil schemes alone won't be enough, right?
一瞬たりとも
Not even for a second.
離れない
Don't leave.
I Love You
こっちをよそ見しないでね
Don't look away from me.
I LOVE POPPY 結局は降りゆーじゃ
I LOVE POPPY, in the end, I'm falling for you
行く先々 アラウンド・ポップ・ア・ビュー
Everywhere I go, it's Around Pop-A-View
ずっと繋いでてね
Keep holding onto me forever
ダッタッタタ リズムに乗って
Da-ta-ta-ta, get into the rhythm
ポケからポッピン 忍ばせポッピ中
Poppin' from my pocket, secretively Poppin' now
踏んだり蹴ったりポッピン かくれんぼ
Through thick and thin, Poppin', hide and seek
ポケからポッピン 忍ばせポッピ中
Poppin' from my pocket, secretively Poppin' now
ぴょん！アラウンド・ポップ・アイドル
Pyon! Around Pop-Idol
Popping Happy to you
ポッピン
Poppin'
ポッピ中
Poppin' now
ほい！
Hoi!
ポッピン
Poppin'
ポッピ中
Poppin' now
ハッとして 乙女乙女乙女の上目して
Gasping in surprise, looking up like a maiden
ピーチミルクシェイク 甘く甘く甘くかきまぜるの
Peach milkshake, stir it sweet, sweet, sweet
群がる野次は行く先々 ラッタッタ歌えば列ができちゃう
Crowds gather wherever I go, sing Rat-ta-ta and a line forms
カラフルララバイもひっくり返る予感 手っ取り早くギュッとになれ！アー
A colorful lullaby about to turn around, hurry up and embrace it! Ah
キラキラ回る星に乗って 時代を回っても
Riding on a sparkling rotating star, even as times change
1足す2になる式はあらず ガブッ！
There's no formula for 1 plus 2 being just that, Chomp!
I LOVE POPPY 置いていかないでね
I LOVE POPPY, don't leave me behind
愛増しまし 全力は降りゆーじゃ
Love keeps growing, full power falling for you
行く先々 アラウンド・ポップ・ア・ビュー
Everywhere I go, it's Around Pop-A-View
ずっと繋いでてね
Keep holding onto me forever
ポケからポッピン 狂わせてポッピ中
Poppin' from my pocket, driving me crazy Poppin' now
行ったり来たりポッピン フローテーション
Back and forth, Poppin', flotation
ポケからポッピン 狂わせてポッピ中
Poppin' from my pocket, driving me crazy Poppin' now
ぴょん！隠れるポップ・アイドル
Pyon! The hiding Pop-Idol
アイ！アイ！アイ！アイ！アイ！アイ！アイ！ブーン！
Ai! Ai! Ai! Ai! Ai! Ai! Ai! Boom!
う〜ポッピン！
Ooh, Poppin'!
う〜ポッピン！ポッピ中
Ooh, Poppin'! Poppin' now
う〜ポッピン！
Ooh, Poppin'!
う〜ポッピン！ポッピ中
Ooh, Poppin'! Poppin' now
どこどこどこどこ わかるかな
Where, where, where, where, can you tell?
100色混じって かなり不安
Mixed with 100 colors, I'm quite anxious
どこどこどこどこ わかるかな
Where, where, where, where, can you tell?
どこにいたって 君が一番
No matter where you are, you're the best
ねえ 遊んで 変わる変わる着せ替えここ 上下左右 アップ・トゥ・ザ・ブーン
Hey, play with me, changing outfits here, left, right, up, down, Up-To-The-Boom
天国地獄地獄 可愛いを作るひと悶着
Heaven, hell, hell, a bit of trouble making things cute
ねえ いつでも呼んで ついてく360度
Hey, call me anytime, I'll follow you 360 degrees
ドクドク夢中中毒
Thump-thump, obsessed and addicted
I LOVE POPPY 置いていかないでね
I LOVE POPPY, don't leave me behind
愛増しまし 全力は降りゆーじゃ
Love keeps growing, full power falling for you
ダッタッタタ ダラダダッタッタタ ダラダダッタッタタ ダース！
Da-ta-ta-ta Da-ra-da-da-ta-ta-ta Da-ra-da-da-ta-ta-ta Dozens!
I LOVE POPPY よそ見しないでね
I LOVE POPPY, don't look away
相も変わらず 結局は降りゆーじゃ
Just like always, in the end, I'm falling for you
行く先々 アラウンド・ポップ・ア・ビュー
Everywhere I go, it's Around Pop-A-View
ずっと繋いでてね
Keep holding onto me forever
ポケからポッピン 忍ばせポッピ中
Poppin' from my pocket, secretively Poppin' now
踏んだり蹴ったりポッピン かくれんぼ
Through thick and thin, Poppin', hide and seek
ポケからポッピン 忍ばせポッピ中
Poppin' from my pocket, secretively Poppin' now
ぴょん！アラウンド・ポップ・アイドル
Pyon! Around Pop-Idol
Poppin' Happy to you
Happy to you
ポッピン
Poppin'
ポッピ中
Poppin' now
はい！
Hai!
ポッピン
Poppin'
ポッピ中
Poppin' now
ポッピン
Poppin'
ポッピ中
Poppin' now
はい！
Hai!
ポッピン
Poppin'
ポッピ中
Poppin' now
はぁ〜、はぁ〜、はぁ〜。ということで、3期生のみんなに来ていただきました！
Haa, haa, haa. And with that, I've had the rest of the 3rd Gen join me!
フレアたん誕生日おめでとう！おめでとう〜！
Flare-tan, Happy Birthday! Congratulations!
いえい！どうもありがとう、ありがとう。
Yay! Thank you so much, thank you.
一応自己紹介しときますか？
Should we do introductions just in case?
一応します？あ、そうね。じゃあ、ぺこちゃんからどうぞ。
Should we? Ah, right. Well then, Peko-chan, you first.
はい！こんぺここんぺここんぺこー！ホロライブ3期生の兎田ぺこらと...
Yes! Kon-peko, kon-peko, kon-peko! I'm Usada Pekora from Hololive 3rd Gen, and...
はい！皆さんこんまっする！ホロライブ3期生脳筋女騎士の白銀ノエルと...
Yes! Kon-massuru everyone! I'm the muscle-brained female knight of Hololive 3rd Gen, Shirogane Noel, and...
アホイ！ホロライブ3期生宝鐘海賊団船長の宝鐘マリンです〜！
Ahoy! I'm the Captain of the Houshou Pirates, Houshou Marine from Hololive 3rd Gen!
そしてみんな合わせて、あ、あ、ああー...
And then everyone together, ah, ah, aah...
こんぬーい、ハーフエルフの不知火フレアです。よろしくお願いします。ホロライブ3期生です。
Kon-nui! I'm the half-elf Shiranui Flare. Nice to meet you. I'm part of Hololive 3rd Gen.
さあ、さあ、3期生4人合わせて...
Now, now, the four of us from 3rd Gen together...
ホロライブ...ホロライブファンタジー！
Hololive... Hololive Fantasy!
はい、いいんじゃない？
Yeah, that was pretty good, right?
こんなことやったっけ？左腕あんた。
Did we ever do that? Your left arm there.
こんなことあったっけ？
Was there ever a moment like that?
いや、いろいろ気になるところがあるんだけど...
Well, there are several things I'm curious about, but...
どうしても真っ先に触れたいのはこの可愛い衣装！
The thing I absolutely have to mention first is this cute outfit!
可愛い！可愛い！可愛い！
It's so cute! Cute! Cute!
でも先に曲の話とかする？
But should we talk about the song first?
あ、そう今日はね、みんなと一緒に歌いたくて、POP-IN 2を歌ったんですけど...
Ah, right. Today, I wanted to sing together with everyone, so we sang POP-IN 2...
本当にね、あの、ここ聴かせたいみたいなところが各々あって。
Everyone had specific parts they really wanted to highlight.
ああ、そうなんだ。
Oh, I see.
だからちょっと歌詞振りをね、みんなが一番なんか、可愛いところをね。
So we adjusted the choreography to show everyone's cutest parts.
いやー、ナイスだわ！
Wow, that's nice!
歌詞振り上手いなと思って、マリリンも。
I thought the choreography was great too.
最高だった。
It was the best.
それだけじゃなくて、あの、その前に歌ったUNDEADのね、コーラスもさ。
Not just that, but the chorus of 'UNDEAD' we sang earlier too...
やったやった！
We did it, we did it!
ア、ア、ア、アってやったね。
We did the 'Ah, ah, ah, ah' part.
そうなの、ありがとうね。
Yeah, that's it. Thank you.
呼んでくれてありがとうー！
Thank you for inviting us!
あんた、可愛いわね、その衣装！
You look so cute in that outfit!
真っ白で可愛い！
It's pure white and so cute!
真っ白ですね。
It's really white.
天使ちゃんみたい、可愛い、可愛い。
You look like an angel. So cute!
ちょっと紹介、じゃあ、足元から順番にちょっと。
Let's introduce it. Starting from the feet.
見せちゃお、見せちゃお。
Let's show it off.
はい、ご覧ください、こちらのこの可愛いブーティーなブーツ！
Take a look at these cute booties!
可愛いーい！
So cute!
ちょっとね、透け感のあるレースが付いてて可愛いですよね。
They have these cute sheer lace details.
さあ、ちょっと上に上がっていっちゃって。
Now, let's move up a bit.
あら、お姫様でちゅかー？
Oh, are you a little princess?
可愛いでしょ。
It's cute, right?
リボン！リボンも可愛い！
The ribbon! The ribbon is so cute too!
ほんのりちょっとオレンジにもなってる。
It's got a slight orange tint.
そう、そうなのよ、透け感もあってね。
Yes, exactly. It has a sheer look too.
可愛い、何でそんな可愛いのー？
So cute! Why are you so cute?
イメージ的には、年中着れる聖歌隊衣装みたいな感じの。
The concept is like a choir outfit that can be worn year-round.
ああ、清楚だ。
Ah, so pure and elegant.
じゃあ、ちょっとお腹らへんから、バストアップらへんいっていいっすか？
Now, can we go from the waist to the bust up?
あらー、可愛い！レディ！
Oh, how cute! Such a lady!
可愛い！あら、後ろも可愛いわね。
Cute! Oh, the back is cute too.
なんか、すごい羽根みたいな、エルフ服みたいだね。
It looks like an elf outfit with those wing-like parts.
ねー、可愛いでしょ。
Right? Isn't it cute?
羽ばたけちゃいそうなんだよ。
You look like you could fly away.
じゃあ、お顔、髪型とかも見る？
Want to see my face and hairstyle too?
え、可愛い！髪型、優勝しとるてー！
Wow, cute! This hairstyle is the best!
ちょっとここ結んでんだ、これ見せて。
It's tied up here. Let me show you.
何付けてんの、これ何付けてんの？
What's this? What's attached here?
あら、ブローチみたいなの付いて、可愛い！
Oh, it's like a brooch. So cute!
あ、本当だ、キラキラ。
Oh, you're right. It's sparkly.
あそこ、編み込み可愛いわね、あんた、それ。
That braid is so cute on you.
あら、髪型もあるのね。
Oh, a new hairstyle too.
可愛い、優勝です！
So cute. You win!
いや、でも、マリンとしては一個気になるな。
But there's one thing I'm curious about.
なに、なに、マリン、なんかある？
What is it, Marine? Something on your mind?
あのー、もう露出！脱げない、脱げないのかな、それ、ちょっと一枚くらい。
I want more skin! Can't you take off a layer?
やだ、もう、おじさん、脱げないのそれ？
Oh stop, you old man. Can you take it off though?
これはねー、なんと、脱げます！
Well, actually, I can!
え！脱げる？せーの、脱げー！
What! You can? One, two, take it off!
じゃあ、ちょっと、まあ、でも、ちょっとだけ脱げる、ちょっとだけ。
Well, I can take off just a little bit.
じゃあちょっと脱いできて、脱いできて！
Go take it off then, go go!
ペコらも大丈夫なのかな、どこ脱いでくるんだろう。
I wonder if it's okay. What part is she taking off?
じゃあ、フレちゃんが脱いでる間に、マリンが一枚脱ごうかな。
While Flare-chan is changing, maybe I'll take something off too.
お前はいいよ、お前お腹出てるし。
Not you. Your belly is already out.
脱げましたよー！
I'm back!
え！どこ、どれ？あら、可愛いわー！
Where? Which part? Oh, how cute!
ちょっとじっくり見せて、おばさんによく見せて。
Show me properly. Let this old lady have a look.
待って待って。
Wait, wait.
待って、あら、可愛ーい！
Wait, oh, how cute!
背中が！背中が可愛い！
The back! The back is so cute!
ちょっと腕上げてみて、はい、バンザーイ。
Try raising your arms. Hands up!
バンザーイ！
Hands up!
はい、くるり。
Now, spin around.
あら、可愛ーい！
Oh, so cute!
めちゃめちゃ天使、いい！
Total angel. I love it!
シェイプ取れててめっちゃ可愛い。
The silhouette is so cute.
でもね、実は、この衣装、もう一個秘密があって。
But actually, there's one more secret to this outfit.
え、まだあるの！？
What, there's more!?
もっといいんですか？もっと脱げるのか？
Is it even better? Are you taking more off?
脱げないけど、待ってて。
I'm not taking anything off, but wait.
やばいな、サービスだぞと。
Oh man, it's fanservice time.
サービス、サービス来た！
Fanservice! Here it comes!
お願いします、何、何？
Please! What is it?
どうかしら。
How about this?
あら、可愛ーい！
Oh, so cute!
星空というか、ね、なんか、聖歌隊みたいな感じをイメージして。
Like a starry sky... I went for a choir-like feel.
ちょっとだけ、紺というか、水色っぽい感じのね。
It's a bit navy or light blue.
あんた、似合うわね、星屑イメージにして。
It really suits you, with that stardust theme.
星屑イメージにしてみました。
I tried to make it look like stardust.
神秘的！お姫様みたい！
So mystical! Like a princess!
撮んね、パシャ、パシャ、パシャ。
Taking photos! Click, click, click.
みんな、写真撮んだ、パシャパシャ、スクショタイム！
Everyone, take photos! Click click, screenshot time!
全然印象変わるね、これ。
This gives a totally different impression.
これね、なんか、帽子も実は取れたりとかする。
And actually, I can take the hat off too.
え！ちょっと見せて、ご覧なさい、帽子も脱いで。
What! Show us, let's see you without the hat.
なんと、脱いじゃう。
I'm taking it off then.
フレア、行くぞ、ファッションショー楽しいね。
Go Flare! This fashion show is fun.
生誕祭ファッションショーよ。
It's a birthday fashion show.
フレちゃん、急がないで、じっくり脱げばいいんだから。
Flare-chan, don't rush. Take your time taking it off.
あら、可愛いじゃないのー！
Oh, how cute!
え、ちょっとじゃあ、見えなかった頭の後ろ側を見せちゃおうよ。
Let's show the back of your head which we couldn't see before.
ああ、本当ね。
Ah, you're right.
可愛いね、似合ってるぺこ。
So cute. It suits you, peko.
ほら、可愛いわ、あんた、最高。
Look how cute you are. You're the best.
こりゃ最高の衣装ですね。
This is truly the best outfit.
ありがとうございます、可愛くデザインしていただきました。
Thank you. I'm so glad it was designed so cutely.
とっても可愛いです。
It's very cute.
歌いたいね！
We want to sing!
あ、アンちゃーん！
Ah, An-chan!
今はないんですけども。
We're not doing it now, though.
え？でもさっき歌ったで...
Eh? But we sang earlier...
歌ったぞ！歌ったぞ！
We did! We did!
オッケー。あら可愛いいわね。
Okay. Oh, how cute.
素敵ねフレアちゃん。じゃあこのまま4人で何かやろうか？
Wonderful, Flare-chan. Shall the four of us do something like this?
じゃあ今から歌うね。今から。
Okay, we're going to sing now. Right now.
いくぞ！
Let's go!
今日はみんなありがとね！
Thanks for today, everyone!
え？え？みんなありがと？
Eh? Eh? Thanks everyone?
じゃああの、お疲れ様！
Well then, good job!
お疲れ様！お疲れ様！
Good job! Good job!
ありがとね！元気で！追い出しすぎ！
Thank you! Take care! You're kicking us out too much!
めっちゃ追い出しすぎや！お〜 お〜
You're kicking us out way too much! Oh, oh!
おめでとう！本当ありがと！可愛かったわよ！
Congrats! Truly thanks! You were cute!
あぁ〜 楽しかったな〜
Ah, that was fun.
ということでですね... え〜
And so... uh...
次の曲は「パレード」でみんなでちょっと盛り上がりたいなということで...
The next song is "Parade", and I want to get hyped with everyone...
ま、ちょっとみんなを追い出しちゃってごめんなさいなんですけど...
Well, sorry for kicking everyone out...
ま、みんなでちょっと盛り上がりたいです！
But I want to get hyped with everyone!
あの曲で... 次の... え？この衣装で...
With that song... next... eh? In this outfit...
次の曲いっちゃうぞ！
Here goes the next song!
Funfair
触れ合えば Don't be afraid
If we touch, don't be afraid
楽しい嬉しい恋し行進！ 前進！ 前進！
Fun, happy, lovely parade! Forward! Forward!
触れ合えば Yes, we are friends
If we touch, yes, we are friends
浮き立ってるウキウキなステップで跳ねるリズミカルに Let's go!
With buoyant, cheerful steps, jumping rhythmically, let's go!
Hi! どこへだって運んであげる。
Hi! I'll take you anywhere.
さながら夢の詰まったオモチャ箱 組み立ててからのお楽しみ。
Like a toy box filled with dreams, the fun starts after it's assembled.
Hi! どこでだって遊んであげる。
Hi! I'll play anywhere.
ラッパのゾウさんにギターのクマと DJ Tiger も従えて。
With a trumpet elephant, a guitar bear, and DJ Tiger in tow.
その土地土地で Make your ドキドキ Day!
In every land, make your heart-pounding day!
つまりあちこちで余興のカチコミです。
In other words, a raid of desires everywhere.
君の街へと大行進 お騒がせしております アイムソーリー。
A grand parade to your town, sorry for the commotion.
キラリぴかぴかの電飾にかけた 魔法に目を奪われる You & You。
Eyes stolen by the magic cast on glittering lights, you & you.
もう注目の的 みんなが噂してる I know I know。
Already the center of attention, everyone's gossiping, I know, I know.
朝から晩までハイテンション 千客万来の大盛況。
High tension from morning till night, a huge success with a flood of visitors.
お待たせ 次は君の番。
Thanks for waiting, next is your turn.
Fun fun fun fun fun funfair!
移り行く君の興味 ずっとここに留まらせる。
I'll keep your shifting interest right here forever.
Ma ma ma ma ma ma Marvelous!
次の街へ 一緒に連れてくよ ほらおいで。
I'll take you to the next town together, come on, join me.
まさにフェスティバル 仲良しこよし 興奮のメーター。
Truly a festival, harmonious and lovely, the excitement meter's high.
掌握テクニカル 求められてるもの理解してるが故のプレイヤー。
Mastering technical skills, a player who understands what's expected.
はい こちらへどうぞ 魅入る声で誘う 現れる本性。
Yes, this way please, inviting with a charming voice, true colors revealed.
失してあげる情習 不安にマイナスな感情 取り除くエモーション。
I'll take away your habitual anxiety, removing negative emotions.
なんだか寂しそう ねえ何か足らない？ (ない)
You look a bit lonely, hey, is something missing? (No)
閉園の時間になっても 帰りたがらない (ない)。
Even at closing time, you don't want to go home (No).
オーキードーキー 差し伸べる手に感じる温もりが何よりのアンサー。
Okey-dokey, the warmth felt in an outstretched hand is the best answer.
ようこそ 今日から君もウチの一員だね。
Welcome, from today you're one of us.
はい それでは Repeat after me! Fun for all!
Alright then, repeat after me! Fun for all!
All for fun! Funfair!
請んじられても Repeat after me! Fun for all!
Even if it's cliché, repeat after me! Fun for all!
All for fun! Funfair!
祭りの後 毎度お馴染み 誰かが噂してる。
After the festival, as usual, someone's gossiping.
I know.
街から人がいなくなってる。
People are disappearing from the town.
奴らが何やら企んでる はてさて次は誰の番。
They're plotting something... well now, whose turn is next?
Fun fun fun fun fun funfair!
移り行く君の興味 ずっとここに留まらせる Get you!
I'll keep your shifting interest right here forever, get you!
Ma ma ma ma ma ma Marvelous!
次の街へ 一緒に連れてくよ ほらおいで。
I'll take you to the next town together, come on, join me.
幾つもの街を巡り巡って。
Traveling through many towns.
浮かない顔の君にあげる Good day.
I'll give you a good day for your gloomy face.
空飛ぶ車 煌めく七色のローラーコースター。
A flying car, a glittering seven-colored roller coaster.
ラブリー観覧車 光るキャンディーに誰もがノックアウト。
A lovely Ferris wheel, everyone's knocked out by the glowing candy.
この歌声が聞こえてきたのなら。
If you hear this singing voice...
君の街の番。
It's your town's turn.
Fun fun fun fun fun funfair!
移り行く君の興味 ずっとここに留まらせる Get you!
I'll keep your shifting interest right here forever, get you!
Ma ma ma ma ma ma Marvelous!
次の街へ 一緒に連れてくよ ほらおいで。
I'll take you to the next town together, come on, join me.
Fun for all, all for fun...
Welcome to the funfair さあみんな一緒に Come & Join us!
Welcome to the funfair, now everyone together, come & join us!
ふぅ〜 ということで Funfair でした！どうでした？
Phew, and so that was "Funfair"! How was it?
めちゃくちゃアップテンポで楽しいラップソングになっている曲です。
It's a very up-tempo and fun rap song.
みんな楽しんでいただけましたか？
Did everyone enjoy it?
そしてですね、今回はですね、「フロート」という乗り物まで用意してもらいました。
And this time, I even had a vehicle called a "Float" prepared.
ありがとうございます！すごいよねこれ。
Thank you very much! This is amazing, isn't it?
今回はねちょっとパレードしてみたいなと思ったんでね。
I wanted to have a little parade this time.
ご用意させていただきました。ありがとうございます！
So I had it prepared. Thank you very much!
みんなもありがとう！
Thank you to everyone too!
さて...
Well...
...えー、恒例の...
...uh, the usual...
告知タイムいきましょうか！
let's get to the announcement time!
あ、でもね、まだあの、終わらないので
Ah, but wait, it's not over yet,
ちょっと、まだこれ、終わる、本当の最後まで見ててほしいんですけど
so I want you to watch until the very end.
えー、今年の告知はですね、二つあります！
Um, this year's announcements, I have two!
あ、これだと四つか。二つあります！
Oh, that's four. I have two!
では、えー、まず一つ目はこちら！
So, um, first one is this!
今年も出します、不知火フレア生誕祭グッズ2025！
I'm releasing them again this year, Shiranui Flare Birthday Celebration Goods 2025!
はい、気になる内容、みんなと一緒に見ていきましょう！一つ目はこちら！
Yes, let's look at the exciting contents together! First one is this!
アクリルジオラマスタンド！
Acrylic Diorama Stand!
さいきやひろ先生に描いていただきました。可愛いでしょ！
It was drawn by Saiki Yahiro-sensei. Isn't it cute?
えー、この衣装もですね、えー、さいきやひろ先生にデザインしていただきました。
Um, this outfit too, was designed by Saiki Yahiro-sensei.
本当にありがとうございました！可愛いー！
Thank you so much! It's so cute!
ま、今回ね、衣装に合わせて神秘的な感じに仕上げていただきました。ありがとうございました。
Well, this time, it was finished with a mystical feel to match the outfit. Thank you very much.
えー、続いて、えー、二つ目はこちら！
Um, continuing on, the second one is this!
ランダムラバーストラップ！
Random Rubber Strap!
ま、四周年にもね、出させていただいたんですけど、ま、今回はですね、違うパターンのラバーストラップです！
Well, I released them for my 4th anniversary too, but this time, it's a different pattern of rubber straps!
なんか、ん？なんか見たことない衣装とかも、ちょっとあるけど... まぁまぁまぁ、一旦、一旦ね。一旦、さておき。
Wait, huh? There are some outfits I haven't seen before... Well, anyway, for now, let's set that aside.
えー、ま、今回もね、いろんな衣装出ましたので、えー、ぜひぜひ、お願いしまーす。ということで。
Um, well, various outfits appeared this time as well, so um, please check them out. Moving on.
イラストはですね、四周年記念グッズと同じく、えー、いつもお世話になっております、雨三憂ハル先生です。
As for the illustration, same as the 4th anniversary goods, um, it's by Same-ami Uruta-sensei, who I'm always indebted to.
いつも可愛いイラストありがとうございました！
Thank you for always providing such cute illustrations!
えー、次は、こちら！
Um, next is this!
ルミナスパーカー！今回のね、新衣装を表現したパーカーなんですけど、
Luminous Hoodie! It's a hoodie that represents this new outfit,
ま、名前とかついてるほうが、なんか、言いやすいかなーとかって思ったりしたので、えー、ルミナス衣装と、ま、名付けております。
but I thought it might be easier to say if it had a name, so I've named it the "Luminous Outfit."
男女ともに買いやすいデザインにしてもらいましたので、ぜひぜひ皆さん、
I had the design made easy for both men and women to buy, so everyone,
男の子、女の子関係なく、可愛く、かっこよく、えー、おしゃれに、着てもらえたら嬉しいです。
regardless of being a boy or girl, I'd be happy if you wear it cutely, coolly, and stylishly.
サイズも大きいので、重ね着もしやすいです。ぜひぜひお願いします。
The size is large too, so it's easy to layer. Please check it out.
えー、次はですね、こちら！
Um, next is this!
ぬいぐるみキーホルダー、ルミナス衣装バージョン！ういー、可愛いー！可愛いね！
Plushie Keyholder, Luminous Outfit Ver.! Wee, so cute! It's cute!
去年に引き続き、ぬいぐるみのキーホルダーが出ます！
Continuing from last year, a plushie keyholder is being released!
今回は、えー、新衣装のルミナス衣装バージョンです。
This time, um, it's the Luminous Outfit version of the new outfit.
リボンあしらったこの衣装、ま、これの、白いバージョンのほうですね。
This outfit decorated with ribbons, well, it's the white version.
こちらが出ますので、えー、ぜひぜひバックとか、なんか旅行とかね、
Since this is coming out, um, please take it anywhere like your bag or on trips
どこにでも連れてって一緒にフレアとお写真撮ってくれると嬉しいです。
and take photos with Flare, I'd be happy.
おうちに飾ってくれても嬉しいよ！
I'd also be happy if you display it at home!
えー、フルセット購入の特典は、こちら！
Um, the bonus for the full set purchase is this!
えー、数量限定バージョンは、箔押し複製サインに加えて、直筆メッセージが入ります。
Um, the limited quantity version includes a handwritten message in addition to a foil-stamped duplicate signature.
通常バージョンにもですね、箔押し複製サインと箔押し複製メッセージが入りますので、
The regular version also includes a foil-stamped duplicate signature and a foil-stamped duplicate message,
直筆が欲しい方は、ま、先着順とはなってしまうんですけれども、
so if you want the handwritten one, although it's first-come-first-served,
早めに数量限定バージョンをご購入ください。
please purchase the limited quantity version early.
でですね、えーっと、ま、箔押し複製メッセージにはなっちゃうんですけど、
And, um, well, it'll be a foil-stamped duplicate message,
買えなかったよー、数量限定買えなかったよーって方も、
but for those who couldn't buy it, the limited quantity one,
あの、ちょっと長めのメッセージをね、あの、複製のほうは書かせていただきます。
I'll write a slightly longer message for the duplicate version.
なので、えー、ぜひぜひあの、数量買えなくても、ぜひ、あの、悲しまないで買ってくれると嬉しいです。
So, um, please, even if you can't get the limited quantity one, I'd be happy if you buy it without being sad.
さらにですね、えー、フルセット特典として、
Furthermore, um, as a full set bonus,
昨年の九月から発売された、ホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームで使用できるカードが一枚ついてきます！
you'll get one card that can be used in the Hololive Official Card Game, which has been on sale since last September!
えー、カードはホロライブプロダクションオフィシャルカードショップで購入された方のみ対象となります。
Um, the card is only for those who purchased at the Hololive Production Official Card Shop.
特典につくのは、推しをアピールできるキーカード、推しホロメンカードです。
The bonus is a key card to promote your "oshi," an Oshi Holomen Card.
えー、カードの詳細や遊び方については、ホームページに、えー、ホームページ...
Um, for details on the cards and how to play, please check the website, um, the website...
ホームページにてご確認ください。
please check the website.
えー、カードは日本語版のみとなりますので、ご了承ください。
Um, please note that the card will only be in Japanese.
えー、お知らせ二つ目はこちら！ドドン！
Um, the second announcement is this! *drumroll*
新、なんと、なんと！新曲が出ます！
New... what, what! A new song is coming out!
タイトルは、「薄明光線」です！
The title is "Angel's Ladder" (Hakumei Kousen)!
堀江晶太さんに作っていただきました！
It was created by Horie Shota-san!
さっきの、なんかラバーストラップでね、あの見たことない衣装があったなぁ、
About the earlier rubber strap, I thought you might have been like,
みたいな感じだと思ったんですけど、
"Wait, there was an outfit I haven't seen before,"
実はですね、このMVの中でなんと着ている衣装となります。
but actually, it's the outfit I wear in this MV.
えー、ぜひぜひ、えー、このあと配信終了後にMVが公開されます！
Um, please check it out, um, the MV will be released after this stream ends!
えー、各種音楽サイトでは24時からリリースとなっておりますので、ぜひよろしくお願いします。
Um, it will be released on various music sites starting from 24:00, so please check it out.
さて、次がラストの曲になりますが、
Now, the next one will be the last song,
薄明光線、どんな曲か、公開前に聞きたいなー、
and for "Angel's Ladder," I want to hear what kind of song it is before the release,
歌ってほしいなー、なんてね、あるかなー、って、
and I want her to sing it, or something like that... I wonder if there's any of that?
どうしようかなー、歌っちゃおうかなー、歌わないかなー、どうしようかな、いいよ！
What should I do? Should I sing it? Should I not? What should I do? Fine!
ということで、えー、今回「薄明光線」、えー、公開前に歌っちゃおうかなと思います！
So, um, I think I'll sing "Angel's Ladder" this time, um, before the release!
改めまして、今日は来てくれてありがとうございました！
Once again, thank you for coming today!
お疲れ様でした。
Good job, everyone.
それでは、えー、ラスト、締め括る曲、聴いてください。
Now then, please listen to the final song to conclude the show.
「黎明光線」
"Dawn Light Ray"
黎明光線
Dawn Light Ray
オレンジの坂道を登り行けば
If I walk up the orange-hued slope,
懐かしい誰かがそこで待ってる
someone nostalgic is waiting there.
「また、気のせいか」っておどけながら
Joking, "Was it just my imagination again?"
影をすり抜ける
as they slip through the shadows.
これはいつからだっけ まるで夢を見ているようで
Since when was this? It's as if I'm dreaming,
誰かに触れることもなくなって
and even touching someone has ceased.
思い出せない名前
A name I can no longer recall,
だけど大切な思い出
yet it remains a precious memory.
わたしは誰に 逢いたいのでしょう
Who is it that I want to meet?
誰をなくして 泣いているのでしょう
Whom have I lost that makes me cry?
知らないメロディを口ずさむ
Humming a melody I don't know,
いつか此処で 笑っていた
someday, here, I was laughing
あなたと
with you,
with you.
いじらしい天使が残したのは
What the innocent angel left behind
一度だけ世界と 結び合うリボン
was a ribbon that binds with the world just once.
姿形の向こう側へ 祈り込めるもの
A prayer sent beyond the physical form,
伝えたいことがある
there's something I want to tell you.
あったけど いつも上手く言えなかった
There was, but I could never say it well.
声をなくして やっと叫ぶ
Having lost my voice, I finally scream,
なんて情けない亡霊だろう
what a pathetic ghost I must be.
ずっと
Forever,
愛している
I love you.
届くことのない歌と あなたが携えた花を
A song that will never reach, and the flowers you carried,
たった一度だけ 結び合おう
let's bind them together just once.
思い出せなくたって あなたに会いに行く
Even if I can't remember, I'm going to see you.
ずっと
Forever.
光が射す 顔は見えない
The light shines in, I cannot see your face,
それでもなぜかな あなたと分かる
yet for some reason, I know it's you.
知らないメロディを口ずさむ
Humming a melody I don't know,
あなたに教わったんだ
you're the one who taught it to me.
わたしは誰 誰でもいいよ
Who am I? Anyone is fine,
あなたの傍で 泣けるのならば
as long as I can cry by your side.
知らない色をした 空が来る
A sky of unknown colors is approaching.
いつか此処で 笑っていた
Someday, here, I was laughing
あなたと
with you,
with you.
2025年!! 大好きな子たちと今年もたんじょうびをむかえられてすっごく！！うれしいよ！！ みんな愛してる！！ 不知火フレア
2025!! I'm so!! happy to be able to welcome my birthday with my favorite people again this year!! I love you all!! Shiranui Flare